[Music]
welcome to buy Central lunch event 2025
release way 1 in this session we will
show you what is new in interet
reports what we want to show in the
first place that this is feature we
deliver more than two years ago and we
want to show you our standard commitment
to improve existing features so not only
delivering new uh features and even if
this is only regulations uh related to
this feature but we want to work and uh
uh improving existing functionalities
based on your feedback so changes we can
show and we will show in this uh wave
are based on your
feedback okay we have two new features
related to interstat in this wave and
the first one is setting new mandatory
Fields this is something what is
required actually not even for this
inter reports this is required even for
older interstat functionalities to set
up some mandatory fields on your
documents so you will not be situations
not to enter uh this information on time
and then you will have a trouble when
you want to create uh interet reports so
if you set up all these mandatory Fields
you will be en forced to enter all this
information in the moment of posting or
actually before
posting another new feature is related
to multiple V for customers
actually this one is not some it is
based on feedback but it is enforced
with the new functionality we deliver
related to v as we deliver multiple vat
numbers related to customers it has an
impact on interat reporting as well so
changes in interat is related on new V
functionality so now I will switch to my
colleague vmir who will show you how it
works in the practice vadir thank you
Alexander uh so we had previously two
options to choose uh from where do we
pick V number for inter start reporting
and it was either sell to or build to
customer used on the document and in
order to support alternative V uh
numbers we also addit a document option
so V number will be picked directly from
the posted document there is also a
section where you can choose uh which
Fields uh should be mandatory for sales
service purchase uh interat documents uh
before posting so for the purpose of
this demo let's choose transaction type
and transfer method to be
mandatory yep now let's create a sales
order we are in Danish company so let's
create sales order for uh Belgium
customer so this transaction is a
subject for interest start reporting and
let's sell some chairs
we can enable a document checked fact
box so we can see our error missing uh
values straight away so in this case
transaction type must have a value we
can see it right away let's just add
something uh yes now we see that
transformat is
missing let's add transfer method so now
we're ready for posting but before we
post let's just our
default uh ship to
address which is Belgium to something
located in
Germany so we have an option to choose
alternative V
number yes we want to get
lines uh now as you can see uh V
registration number was picked for this
ship to address let's post
and now let's get our interat
report for the
period and we suggest
lines so as you can see uh we have V
number picked on directly from document
and all the mandatory fields are there
just can do a check so everything is
ready no information is missing and yeah
we're ready to report that's it for the
demo thank you vadir great demo and um
what I want to emphasize more we will
show we will we just show two uh new
features but we have some more features
uh we are working uh but they will not
be so visible on user interface uh so it
doesn't mean that uh we are working only
these two so some other technical
improvements will come related to
interstat uh probably
26.12 so we are uh trying to improve
some other things but they cannot be
recognized on a user experience the most
of them but we will publish a
documentation everything what is changed
related with some or regulatory features
or our technical
improvements okay thank you for uh
watching this video